Alison Reilly

reillyamr@gmail.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/alisonreilly/ | Portfolio alisonreilly.dev | Github github.com/Tsunamins

Experienced in Fullstack Development with a background in hospitality. Possess strong skills in critical thinking and need anticipation that help large enterprise companies drive sales and customer experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

TypescriptReactNodePythonRedisSeleniumJestJavaScript

TECHNICAL FOUNDATIONS

Fauxtel Hotels - https://github.com/Tsunamins/FauxtelHotels | https://youtu.be/G4u KgDfBYI

- Created a React with Redux SPA for reservation booking, based on room availability, utilizing react-date-picker
- Added login using JWT token-based authentication and authorization
- Built an API backend using Ruby on Rails, serializing data with fast_jsonapi gem for quick relational access

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer I, Parchment, Remote 9/2022 - present

- Built a front end component library with React and Typescript, improving development speed and UI standardization
- Increased reliability and safeguarded future changes by writing unit tests with React testing-library and Jest
- Demoed components in Storybook and added documentation to communicate updates and implementation instructions
- Promoted and further developed engineer adoption by attending other team meetings to consult on needs and concerns

Software Engineer I, American Express, Remote 12/2021 – 9/2022

- Added front end features for enterprise automations platform using React and company design library
- Implemented API routes in Golang and Python with Flask, concentrating on value add reporting for leadership
- Integrated a Redis Client into backend speeding up reporting and other endpoint times
- Improved automated UI testing coverage by adding pipeline Selenium Browser tests through automated gitlab pipeline

Technical Support Engineer, ServiceNow, Remote | https://www.servicenow.com/ 3/2021 - 12/2021

- Utilized platform debugging tools to identify conflicting security rules and other platform settings
- Employed Chrome Dev Tools, platform tools and other techniques for client side and server side debugging
- Increased ticket resolution speed by coordinating consultations with Customers, team members and developers
- Created knowledge base articles on findings enhancing the available support documentation for users and employees

Backend Developer Intern, **1909 Coworking**, Remote | https://weare1909.org/ 8/2020 - 03/2020 Internship project building middleware and integrations

- Integrated OfficeRnd & Salesforce REST APIs using NodeJS and Firebase functions
- Routed web hook response of OfficeRnd with ExpressJS ensuring separation of concerns
- Communicated goals with product owner and other 1909 team members on a bi-weekly basis to sync goals

EDUCATION

Flatiron School 1/2019 - 03/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript, React, Redux

LaGuardia Community College, Long Island City, NY 3/2013 - 08/2017

Math and Science, Calculus, C++, Biology concentrations